Dobato. What are you up to now?
I'm making some decorations
with this pretty paper.
Isn't that the paper the landlady gave you?
Yes, Ms. Chitose gave it to me
to take to the kindergarten.
She said she won a whole bunch of
them at the shopping district.
I'm going to make lots of decorations like
these to put on the windows and walls.
Do you think that will make everyone happy?!
I think they'll feel stifled.
Why don't I tell you something worthwhile?
That paper is called origami, and origami is
normally used and enjoyed as folding paper.
What?!
Wh... What should I do?! Ioryogi-san?
I can't... I can't put it back the
way it was! Ioryogi-san...
You cut it up already.
How do you expect to put it back together?!
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...Hidden Prayer.
Thanks.
Ms. Sayaka.
You haven't been getting enough
sleep, have you? You look tired.
Now, now.
You don't tell women that they look tired.
You could hurt their feelings.
I'm not joking!
I'll leave this at the office.
Thank you.
U-Um... Ms. Sayaka.
Oh?
Kobato.
I-I'm sorry!
What is it, all of a sudden?
Um... Ms. Chisato gave me these to give
to everyone at the kindergarten.
Oh, origami. So much of it.
Actually there was more, but... I didn't know
that origami was for folding so I messed it up.
I'm really sorry!
Ms. Sayaka?
Ms. Sayaka! Ms. Sayaka!
Fujimoto! Fujimoto!
What is it?
It's Ms. Sayaka!
I'm okay.
Let's get you to the hospital right away.
I'm all right.
You are not all right! Look at you!
Really. I just need a little rest... and I'll be fine.
I know a doctor! I'll go and get him right away!
Kobato?
Kobato, where are you going?
Hello?!
Hello, excuse me! Open the door please!
Will you open the door please? Please!
Kobato?
What's the matter?
Um! Where's Shuichiro?
Please help us. Ms. Sayaka...!
Please!
What's wrong with Ms. Sayaka?
Nothing you have to worry about.
How is she?
She's suffering from fatigue and
gastritis due to lack of sleep.
I see.
I'll prescribe some medication later.
After she's had some rest and feels settled,
feed her something that digests well.
Okay. Thank you for coming
at such short notice.
No worries. Good thing it was my day off.
Uh, um...
Is Ms. Sayaka going to be okay?
If she keeps this up, she'll eventually
end up in much worse condition.
Don't pass it off as simple fatigue.
Please tell her what I just said.
Yes sir.
Well then, take good care of her.
Thank you very much.
How do you know him?
Huh?
That doctor. Who is he?
He lives with Kohaku.
Kohaku?
Oh, that girl from the other day.
Yes.
What is it?
Um... is Teacher Sayaka sick?
She's okay.
Really?
Yeah. The doctor says she'll be fine in no time.
If you put on long faces like that,
Ms. Sayaka is going to worry.
Let's sing a song to help Ms. Sayaka feel better.
Okay!
I see blue, I see blue
Looking up at the big, clear sky
Kobato has completely forgotten about me.
As I feel, as I feel...
Hey.
Y-Yes.
Is just sitting there doing nothing going
to make Ms. Sayaka better?
But just for a little longer...
Get over it already.
She would have much more
peace of mind knowing
that you were looking after the
children properly, wouldn't she?
I guess you're right.
How was it?
How is the patient doing?
Her symptoms have settled.
Is that right? That's good to hear.
And you go like this, and you
go like that, and see? A man!
I get it. So that's how you play with origami.
Look, look, Kobato.
Wow, a balloon!
Toshihiko, what are you folding?
I'm folding cranes.
Cranes?
It's a type of bird.
This is a bird, is it?
You're folding so many.
Mhm. One thousand!
Huh? One thousand? That many?
Yup. If I fold one-thousand cranes while
praying for Teacher Sayaka to get better,
she's going to get better.
Toshihiko!
Can you show me how to fold this crane too?!
I'll fold some too!
I'm going to fold cranes too!
Me too!
Then let's all fold them together!
I wonder if Kobato's all right.
Shouldn't you be worrying about the patient?
Oh of course. You're right. But...
Why is it? For some reason, I can't
help but worry about Kobato.
Will Teacher Sayaka be better by tomorrow?
She'll be fine!
Besides, we've folded one-thousand cranes!
Mhm!
I'll be back from work as soon as I can.
You take good care of Ms. Sayaka.
Yes.
If anything happens, call me right away.
Excuse me, I have a request.
Seems serious. What is it?
Would it be possible to cut
my hours back for awhile?
I thought you needed the money.
Well that's true, but...
Right now I...
Sure. No problem.
But when you're back on track
I'm going to work you hard.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Thank you very much.
Ms. Sayaka.
Kobato?
Were you here with me the whole time?
Yes.
What about the children?
Their families came to pick them up
and they've all gone home.
Oh. I'm so sorry to have worried you.
No, don't get up yet. Please.
I thought I had myself pulled together.
Huh?
With you helping out, I guess
somewhere I had let loose,
knowing that I could count on you and Fujimoto.
If something ever happens to me...
What makes you say such a thing?!
Don't... Don't even...
I can't imagine something happening to you.
That would make everyone too sad. So please...
Don't ever say such a thing again!
Kobato.
You've helped enough. Go home now.
Huh?
You're clumsy as it is.
I don't need you to become double clumsy
because you didn't get enough sleep.
Double clumsy?!
I'm not that clumsy!
Just leave the rest to me and go home.
Okay.
Don't be clumsy and stumble on your way.
I am not that bad.
Just go.
She scolded me.
Good for her, considering.
I guess so. Kobato is right.
The children. They all folded.
Is that so?
This is a crane she folded.
Agh, all these over here are hers.
She's a good kid.
Are you that worried about Sayaka?
Hey Kobato.
Huh?
No, never mind.
Okay.
Could she be regaining that memory she lost?
Hanamaro Drill
Language
"I did it!"
"It's fun!"
Hanamaro Drill
Language
"I did it!"
"It's fun!"
Chiho, what's the answer to number seven?
What, Chise, don't you know either?
Kobato.
It's Kobato.
Um... Is Ms. Chisato here?
Mom's at a neighborhood meeting.
Oh is that right?
What's the matter?
You look sad, Kobato.
Actually...
I'm worried about an illness!
Oh no, Kobato!
No, no, no, not me!
Huh?
Ms. Sayaka is sick.
I want to do something for her,
but I don't know what to do?
I tried folding one-thousand
cranes with everybody.
One-thousand cranes.
Yes.
But I couldn't fold them very well and I'm
afraid that because of my poor folding,
our wish won't come true.
Don't worry, Kobato.
I'm certain that your wish will come true.
I certainly hope so.
Oh, how about that?
You know, when we're sick,
Mom always makes it for us.
Rice porridge...
That's right, rice porridge.
Of course, rice porridge
Mom says porridge is easy to digest,
so it's not too hard on your
stomach even when you're sick.
Easy to digest?
Come to think of it,
Shuichiro said the same thing.
To give Ms. Sayaka something that digests well.
Then Kobato, make her some rice porridge.
Mhm. That will make Ms. Sayaka better for sure.
Yes! I will make rice porridge for Ms. Sayaka!
But how do I make rice porridge?
I know. Chiho, why don't you draw a picture?
Great idea, Chise!
It looks kind of like this.
This is rice porridge?
It's white and...
Kind of gooey, I think.
That's right. It's gooey!
Gooey
Oh and when we eat it, Mom would tell us,
"be careful or you'll burn your tongue".
Very hot!
And when she made it she
would add lots of water.
Full of water!
Amazing.
I have an uneasy feeling about this.
Who is it?!
What are you doing?!
I was trying... to make rice porridge.
Very hot
How to make rice porridge
White
Easy to digest
Gooey
Very hot
How to make rice porridge
White
Easy to digest
Gooey
After all that effort Chiho and Chise
made to show me how...
Very hot
How to make rice porridge
White
Easy to digest
Gooey
and I couldn't get it right.
Apparently rice porridge is
good for the digestion.
That's why I thought Ms. Sayaka...
First, you wash the rice you'll use,
and then add lots of water.
Put it over the heat until it boils.
After that, let it stew over low heat. That's it.
How in the world do you come
up with that concoction?
Feed her something like that
and she'll just get worse.
C-Come on, don't cry.
If Ms. Sayaka dies...
Don't worry. People don't die that easily.
Sometimes they do!
Sometimes it doesn't take very
much for someone to die.
Did that happen to someone you know?
It's all right.
Ms. Sayaka is not going to die.
It's okay.
Oh this is good! I'll be a hundred times better!
I'm glad!
But I might end up eating too much.
Mmm, delicious.
I'm glad I could be of some help.
Although I actually did most of the cooking.
W-Well that's true, but...
But what?
Nothing at all.
I didn't think so.
It's not like there are any more than there were.
You don't get more kompeito by
just looking at them, you know!
Yes!
But you're not upset.
Come to think of it...
I wonder why.
When I cried...
When I cried as hard as I could
in front of Fujimoto...
It was as if this heaviness in
my heart lightened up,
and I was left with this very warm feeling.
So what now? You're supposed to be healing
others but you're letting others heal you.
Heal me?
Is this what?
Good morning!
Morning.
It's Teacher Sayaka!
Good morning!
Good morning, Teacher Sayaka!
Good morning.
Are you all better now?
I'm all better now.
So the thousand cranes worked?
Good morning, Kobato!
Yes! Good morning!
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Mysterious Life Form.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Mysterious Life Form.